Register of the United Nations Conference on International Organization proceedings
Hoover Institution Archives
- National Broadcasting Company Sound Recordings of Proceedings, 1945 (Boxes 3-6)
  - Proceedings of Commission I, Committee 1, 1945 June 15 (Box 5)
    Malcolm Davis reads the text of documents before the committee, Victor Andres Belaunde of Peru passionately speaks on the importance of a nation's personality, Hanna Saba speaks about police powers and the use of force, a delegate from Colombia defends his amendment, Dean Virginia C. Gildersleeve, a delegate from Ukranian S.S. Republic on the Yalta agreement, the Viscount Cranborne discusses the proposal of the Ukrainian delegate and the pre-WWII world, Herbert Vere Evatt responds to Cranborne, Ricardo J. Alfaro, and Peter Fraser.
  - Proceedings of Commission IV, Committees 1 and 2, 1945 June 15 (Boxes 5, 6)
    Speakers: Manuel Gallagher, Nasarat All-Farici, a delegate from Iran, Herbert Vere Evatt, Abdel Hamid Badawi Pasha, and Mariano Arguello Vargas.
    Parts 6 and 8 are unavailable due to the source disc being broken.
  - Proceedings of Commission III, Committee 2, 1945 June 18 (Box 5)
    Speakers: G. P. Arkadiev, Herbert Vere Evatt, and Comm. Harold E. Stassen USNR.
  - First session of Commission I, Committees 1 and 2, 1945 June 19 (Box 4)
    Speakers: Hector Paysse Reyes, Fernand de Housse, Charles A. Eaton, Lord Cranborne, Malcolm Davis, Luis Quintanilla, Joseph Paul-Boncour on the problems of the League of Nations, Herbert Vere Evatt, Alexander V. Palladin, Kuzma B. Kisilev, James C. Dunn, Jose Serrato, and Francisco Villagran. Concerns Mexico's comments on Franco's Spain and any membership in the United Nations.
    Parts 1 and 3 are unavailable due to the source disc being broken.
  - Second session of Commission I, Committees 1 and 2, 1945 June 19 (Boxes 4, 6)
    Speakers: Malcolm Davis, Alfredo Machado Hernandez, a delegate from Greece, a delegate from France, Peter Fraser, Bertha Lutz, Cemil Bilsel, L. B. Pearson, and Hector Paysse Reyes.
    Parts 1 and 3 are unavailable due to the source disc being cracked.
  - First session of Commission III, Committee 1, 1945 June 20 (Box 4)
    Concerns the Security Council.
    Speakers: Hector David Castro, Alfonso Garcia Robles, Abdel Hamid Badawi Pasha, Herbert Vere Evatt, Senator Tom Connally, a delegate from Cuba, Grayson Kirk.
  - Second session of Commission III, Committees 1 and 3, 1945 June 20 (Box 4)
    Speakers: Alexander Loudon, Alberto Lleras Camargo, Victor Andres Belaunde, Peter Fraser, Sir A. Ramaswami Mudaliar, Hector David Castro, John Sofianopoulos, Joseph Paul-Boncour, Ato Ambaye Wolde Marian, Hugh H. Wrong, and Denis Capel-Dunn.
    Several delegations passionately comment on the veto power in the Security Council.
  - Proceedings of Commission II, Committee 4, 1945 June 20 (Box 4)
    Speakers: Alexander Loudon, Emile Naggiar, Fadhil Al-Jamali, Francis Michael Forde, Carlos P. Romulo, Lord Cranborne on colonial governance, Auguste de Schryver, Mohamed Awad of Egypt, Harold E. Stassen, and Peter Fraser on independence and interdependence.
  - Proceedings of Commission II, Committees 1 and 2, 1945 June 21 (Boxes 4, 6)
    Speakers: a delegate from Peru, Herbert Vere Evatt, Victor Andrade, Ali Akbar Siassi, Raoul Aglion, V. K. Wellington Koo, a delegate from Uruguay, Henri Rolin, C. K. Webster, a delegate from Colombia, Adly Bey Andrawes, Jose Maza, and Luis Padilla Nervo.
    Parts 6 and 8 are unavailable due to the source disc being cracked.
  - Proceedings of Commission I, Committees 1 and 2, 1945 June 23 (Box 3)
    Speakers: Francisco A. Delgado, Herbert Vere Evatt.
  - Recognition of the secretariat, 1945 June 23 (Box 3)
    The co-presidents of the conference give their thoughts and thanks to all the participants of the conference.
    Presiding: Edward R. Stettinius Jr.; V. K. Wellington Koo; Andre A. Gromyko; the Earl of Halifax; and Alger Hiss.
  - Ninth plenary session, 1945 June 25 (Box 3)
    Presiding: The Earl of Halifax.
    Speakers: Hugues Le Gallais, Francisco A. Delgado, Andre A. Gromyko, Ricardo J. Alfaro, Celso R. Velasquez, Caracciolo Parra-Perez, Guillermo Belt Ramirez, Edward R. Stettinius Jr., and Alger Hiss.
  - President Truman arriving at Hamilton Field, 1945 June 25 (Box 3)
    President Truman arrives at Hamilton Field to a formal ceremony. He came to San Francisco to sign the United Nations charter. Also includes coverage of Truman visiting wounded soldiers.
  - Signing of the United Nations Charter, 1945 June 26 (Box 3)
    NBC coverage of the signing of the United Nations charter and comments by each nation's delegation.
    The nations in order: China, Soviet Union, United Kingdom, Argentina, France, Uruguay, Australia, Belgium, Bolivia, Brazil, Belarus, Chile, Costa Rica, Canada, Columbia, Cuba, Dominican Republic, Ecuador, Czechoslovakia, Egypt, El Salvador, Denmark, Ethiopia, Greece, Haiti, Honduras, India, Iraq, Lebanon, Luxembourg, Iran, Liberia, the Netherlands, Mexico, Norway, New Zealand, Nicaragua, United States, Paraguay, Peru, Saudi Arabia, Panama, Philippines, South Africa, Turkey, Syria, Venezuela, Yugoslavia, and Guatemala.
    Ukraine is mentioned just before Venezuela, but a Ukrainian delegate is not part of the recording.
  - Final plenary session, 1945 June 26 (Box 3)
    Speakers: V. K. Wellington Koo, A. A. Gromyko, the Earl of Halifax, Joseph Paul-Boncour, Pedro Leao Velloso, Jan Masaryk, Ezequiel Padilla, Amir Faisal Ibn Abdul Aziz, Jan Christian Smuts, and Harry S. Truman.
- 2017 Incremental Materials (Boxes 7-21)
  Not yet described.